Guide to the Randy Cunningham Collection on the New American Movement TAM.806
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Randy Cunningham Collection on the New American Movement
1977-1981
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Cunningham, Randy, (Political Activist)
TAM.806
.75 linear feet in 1 manuscript box and 1 half manuscript box
Randy Cunningham is a Cleveland-based activist and writer. He is a founding member of the Cuyahoga County Progressive Caucus. Cunningham was the Chair of New American Movement's Urban and Community Commission during the late-1970s and early-1980s, working on campaigns that focused on rent control in Dayton Ohio. As a member of the Mad River (Dayton) chapter he helped organize workshops and conventions on urban issues. The Randy Cunningham Collection on the New American Movement (dated 1977-1981) consists of materials collected by Cunningham during his time with the socialist organization the New American Movement (NAM) before it merged with the Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee (DSOC) to form Democratic Socialists of America (DSA). Materials include drafts of NAM's The Primitive Socialist City Project, materials from the Baltimore Urban Organizing Conference, Urban and Community Commission correspondence, and political education and campaign materials from Baltimore, Dayton, and Pittsburgh.
Scope and Contents
The Randy Cunningham Collection on the New American Movement (dated 1977-1981) consists of materials collected by Cunningham during his time with the socialist organization the New American Movement (NAM) before it merged with the Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee (DSOC) to form Democratic Socialists of America (DSA). Materials include drafts of NAM's The Primitive Socialist City Project, materials from the Baltimore Urban Organizing Conference, Urban and Community Commission correspondence, and political education and campaign materials from Baltimore, Dayton, and Pittsburgh.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Randy Cunningham in January 2022; the accession number associated with this gift is 2022.007.
Biographical Note
Randy Cunningham is a Cleveland-based activist and writer. He is a founding member of the Cuyahoga County Progressive Caucus. Cunningham was the Chair of New American Movement's Urban and Community Commission during the late-1970s and early-1980s, working on campaigns that focused on rent control in Dayton Ohio. As a member of the Mad River (Dayton) chapter he helped organize workshops and conventions on urban issues.
Socialist parties -- United States.; New Left -- United States.; City planning -- Social aspects; Cunningham, Randy, (Political Activist); New American Movement (Organization)
- Primitive Socialist City, circa 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
- Baltimore Urban Organizing Conference, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Rent Control Reader, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Basic Political Education Course (New American Movement), circa 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- New American Movement Urban and Community Commission, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- New American Movement Urban and Community Commission -- Letters, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 8-11)
- New American Movement Convention, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- City Life in the 80s Conference, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Winning Rent Control in a Working-Class City, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- New American Movement -- Urban and Community Commission -- General, 1978-1981 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Conference on Alternative Policies; Metropolis, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 4)